<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Gustavo Burin</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Gustavo Burin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Gustavo Burin</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My new paper is out @ Systematic Biology!</title>
      <link>/my-new-paper-is-out--systematic-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/my-new-paper-is-out--systematic-biology/</guid>
      <description>The new paper from my PhD dissertation is finally out! In this study, we used computational simulations of phylogenies under different diversity decline scenarios to test for the performance of two recently developed, widely used methods for estimating diversification rates from molecular phylogenies. We found that both BAMM and RPANDA estimate well both speciation and extinction rates at the present, but the further one goes to the past the worse the estimates are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our new paper is out!</title>
      <link>/our-new-paper-is-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/our-new-paper-is-out/</guid>
      <description>The new paper from our lab is out! In this study, Dr. Laura Alencar explores if the evolution of arboreality in vipers affects species and morphological diversification regimes. We found out that although arboreal vipers evolve under a more constrained morphological trajectories compared to terrestrial vipers, speciation rates remain similar. This study was part of her PhD thesis, and was featured in the cover of Proceedings B with a beautiful image by one of the authors, Marcio Martins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My defense presentation</title>
      <link>/my-defense-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 14:05:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/my-defense-presentation/</guid>
      <description>I defended my dissertation on October 2nd, and here are the slides from my talk</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My talk @ Evolution Meeting, 2017</title>
      <link>/my-talk--evolution-meeting-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 14:05:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/my-talk--evolution-meeting-2017/</guid>
      <description>I just found out (almost by accident) that the filming of my talk at the Macroevolution I session during the Evolution meeting last June in Portland, OR, is online (click here or on the image to watch it on youtube).
Please, feel free to leave any feedback! Any suggestion will be greatly appreciated!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first paper is available</title>
      <link>/my-first-paper-is-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 14:05:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/my-first-paper-is-available/</guid>
      <description>I just found out (almost by accident) that the filming of my talk at the Macroevolution II session during the Evolution meeting last month in Guarujá, Brazil, is online (click here or on the image to watch it on youtube).
Please, feel free to leave any feedback! Any suggestion will be greatly appreciated!

If the image quality is not so good, you can see the slides in this link.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first paper is available</title>
      <link>/my-first-paper-is-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 14:05:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/my-first-paper-is-available/</guid>
      <description>Last month my first paper got published a year after the first submission. In this paper we assess how diet affects the macroevolutionary dynamics of all bird species, and found that omnivores - species that feed on multiple food items - have lower (even negative) net diversification. This pattern arises from either smaller speciation and/or greater extinction when compared to all other dietary guilds.
Associated with that, there is a prevalence of transitions from all guilds into omnivory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial de SSH</title>
      <link>/tutorial-de-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 14:05:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorial-de-ssh/</guid>
      <description>SSH é a sigla para &amp;lsquo;Secure SHell&amp;rsquo;, e é basicamente um protocolo de rede que permite computadores se conectarem via rede de forma a permitir que um computador execute comandos em unidades remotas de maneira segura (criptografada). Essa segurança é garantida por uma chave de segurança que é armazenada tanto em no computador local quanto na máquina remota. Além disso, na maioria das vezes esse acesso é somente autorizado através de senhas de acesso.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial de ggplot2</title>
      <link>/tutorial-de-ggplot2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 14:05:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorial-de-ggplot2/</guid>
      <description>O pacote ggplot2 foi desenvolvido pelo Dr. Hadley Wickham (que desenvolveu diversos outros pacotes importantes para R como o (d)plyr por exemplo. Este pacote implementa uma nova maneira de criar gráficos a partir dos dados, trazendo o conceito de camadas (layers) para a sintaxe do R. Com esse novo conceito, surge também a necessidade de se organizar os dados de uma maneira que facilite a utilização da nova sintaxe. Para isso, os outros pacotes (como os já mencionados (d)plyr) foram desenvolvidos pelo Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>